{
  "questions": [
    {
      "question": "Which of the following syntax correctly declares an Array?",
      "options": [
      "int geeks;", 
      "array geeks[20];", 
      "geeks{20};", 
      "int geeks[20];"
    ],
      "correctOption": 3,
      "points": 10
    },
    {
      "question": "The size of the array should always be _____",
      "options": ["Positive", "Negative", "Whole Number", "Real Number"],
      "correctOption": 0,
      "points": 10
    },
    {
      "question": "What is the correct way to initialize values in an array?",
      "options": [
        "my_array [5] = (5,3,4,2,7);", 
        "my_array [5] = {5;3;4;2;7};", 
        "my_array [5] = {5,3,4,2,7,5,6,7,8};", 
        "my_array [5] = {1,2,3,4,5}"
      ],
      "correctOption": 3,
      "points": 10
    },
    {
      "question": "In an array int arr[3]={1,2,3}, what will happen if we try to access arr[4] in C/C++?",
      "options": [
        "Run Time Error", 
        "3", 
        "0", 
        "Garbage value"
      ],
      "correctOption": 3,
      "points": 10
    },
    {
      "question": "Which of these operators can be used to concatenate two or more String objects?",
      "options": [
        "'+'",
        "'+='",
        "'&'",
        "None of these"
      ],
      "correctOption": 0,
      "points": 10
    },
    {
      "question": "Which of these methods of class String is used to obtain the length of the String object?",
      "options": [
        "get()", 
        "Sizeof()", 
        "lengthof()", 
        "length()"
    ],
      "correctOption": 3,
      "points": 10
    },
    {
      "question": "In a circular linked list, the last node points to the____.",
      "options": [
        "this pointer",
        "tall pointer",
        "first node",
        "middle node"
      ],
      "correctOption": 2,
      "points": 20
    },
    {
      "question": "What advantage does a linked list have over an array?",
      "options": [
        "A linked list is not of a fixed size",
        "It's Better",
        "It's Easier to use",
        "A linked list can give you the data faster"
      ],
      "correctOption": 0,
      "points": 30
    },
    {
      "question": "Nodes in a linked list contain two things:",
      "options": [
        "A pointer and a node",
        "A Pointer and a reference",
        "Direction and a pointer",
        "Data and a pointer"
      ],
      "correctOption": 3,
      "points": 20
    },
    {
      "question": "The last node of the singly-linked list contains ___",
      "options": [
        "NULL",
        "Next Pointer",
        "Data",
        "None of the above"
      ],
      "correctOption": 0,
      "points": 30
    },
    {
      "question": "How many null pointers exist in a circular linked list?",
      "options": ["0", "1", "2", "3"],
      "correctOption": 0,
      "points": 30
    },
    {
      "question": "The process of inserting an element in the stack is called ____________",
      "options": ["create", "Evaluate", "push", "pop"],
      "correctOption": 2,
      "points": 10
    },
    {
      "question": "In a stack, if a user tries to remove an element from an empty stack it is called?",
      "options": [
        "Empty Collection",
        "Garbage Collection",
        "Overflow",
        "Underflow"
      ],
      "correctOption": 3,
      "points": 30
    },
    {
      "question": "The list of data in which elements can be inserted and removed at the same end is called ____.",
      "options": [
        "Array",
        "Queue",
        "Stack",
        "None"
      ],
      "correctOption": 2,
      "points": 30
    },
    {
      "question": "Which data structure type allows deleting data elements from front and inserting at rear?",
      "options": [
        "Array",
        "Queue",
        "Stack",
        "None"
      ],
      "correctOption": 1,
      "points": 20
    }
  ]
}